<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robin Tolochko</title>
    <description>Robin Tolochko Map nerd | UI/UX | Front-end design
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 21:26:01 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 21:26:01 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 19:34:16 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2015/11/23/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2015/11/23/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ode to Honey and Papa</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;500px&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://a.tiles.mapbox.com/v4/tolomaps.o4bg0ag4/attribution,zoompan,geocoder,share.html?access_token=pk.eyJ1IjoidG9sb21hcHMiLCJhIjoiREpQUkpiTSJ9.g4b1dVMvmEB78zMOSgiHIA&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About:&lt;/strong&gt;
I made this map in memory of my maternal grandparents, Carol and Van Hart, fondly known as Honey and Papa. My parents, aunts, uncles, cousins, and siblings helped me compile a list of places that were meaningful to Honey and Papa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Process:&lt;/strong&gt;
The colors for the map came from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/yxILddEUfI/?tagged=montgomerytour&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;the stained glass&lt;/a&gt; at the old train station in Montgomery, Alabama, where my grandparents were from. The inspiration to create the map came after a visit to Montgomery for Honey’s funeral, and driving around to see all of the important places in her life (and my childhood).
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I created all of the textures in Photoshop, the texture of each color distinct from the rest. I created the map in Mapbox Studio Classic with custom CartoCSS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2015/11/01/ode-to-honey-and-papa.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2015/11/01/ode-to-honey-and-papa.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>portfolio</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Colombia Cycling</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;portfolio-asset&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../../../../assets/portfolio/colombia-cycling.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/portfolio/colombia-cycling.png&quot; alt=&quot;Colombia Cycling Map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About:&lt;/strong&gt;
The assignment for this class project was to create a map for a cycling competition for anywhere in the world and display it on a shaded relief terrain map. Naturally, I chose Colombia as the site for my fake competition, considering I lived there for several years and Colombia is well-known for its high-caliber cyclists. I created a totally unrealistic and ridiculous route, taking cyclists through known dangerous areas, up and down the Andes Mountains numerous times. Because why not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Process:&lt;/strong&gt;
I created the shaded relief in Blender, thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://somethingaboutmaps.wordpress.com/2014/01/01/blender-tutorial/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Daniel Huffman’s excellent tutorial&lt;/a&gt;. After I got the hang of it, I loved working with Blender and think that it produces much more realistic shaded relief than the default methods that are often used.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2015/10/15/colombia-cycling.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2015/10/15/colombia-cycling.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>portfolio</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Real Cost of Child Care</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;About:&lt;/strong&gt;
This is a piece for my Graphic Design in Cartography class. The assignment was to make an infographic with a bivariate map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Process:&lt;/strong&gt;
Read about &lt;a href=&quot;http://tolomaps.tumblr.com/post/131671267233/creating-a-bivariate-choropleth-color-scheme&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;my process for creating a bivariate choropleth color scheme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background:&lt;/strong&gt;
In 1971, Congress passed a bipartisan bill that would have “established a network of nationally funded, locally administered, comprehensive child care centers, which were to provide quality education, nutrition, and medical services.” And then Nixon vetoed it, because he said that children should be raised by family (read: women shouldn’t work). We were so close to universal public child care. It’s never been on the table since then, even though we provide free, public education to all children starting in kindergarten. Why shouldn’t we start earlier?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started working on this project as a selfish exploration (paying for child care is expensive), but the more I learned, the more I think this should be a national priority. Providing young kids with high-quality child care is the best thing that we can do for their long-term development and our country’s future economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/portfolio/cost-of-childcare-infographic.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Real Cost of Childcare&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2015/09/30/the-real-cost-of-child-care.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2015/09/30/the-real-cost-of-child-care.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>portfolio</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Astro Digital</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;portfolio-asset&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/portfolio/astro-digital-profile.png&quot; alt=&quot;Astro Digital profile page&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
While doing a 2015 summer fellowship at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.developmentseed.org&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Development Seed&lt;/a&gt;, my main client was Astro Digital, a start-up that lets you easily search and publish satellite imagery through their &lt;a href=&quot;https://fetch.astrodigital.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;imagery browser&lt;/a&gt;. My main role on the project was working on the user profile accounts, where you can store all of your published maps in one place and set alerts to let you know when new imagery is available in areas that you want to track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I led the discussion on how to direct users through the website and create a cohesive experience. When I came on the project, there was no connection between the imagery browser and the user profile, which were built as two separate applications. The two platforms looked and felt detached from each other. I created wireframes for how the site should flow from one platform to the other to create a seamless experience. This also included figuring out how users should create accounts and log in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The imagery browser originally had the interactive map on the left-hand side of the page, with the available imagery on the right-hand side. It also had the filter buttons on the top menu bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original design for the Astro Digital imagery browser:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/portfolio/astro-digital-fetch-old.png&quot; alt=&quot;Astro Digital old imagery browser&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I proposed that we swap the placement of the interactive map and the available imagery to match the layout of the user profile. I also proposed moving the filter buttons from the top navigation bar to be on top of the map. This allows the blue navigation bar to match across the two platforms, as well as place the buttons that affect the map results to be on top of the map itself. Clearing up the blue navigation bar also gives space to put the user’s name and avatar in the top-right corner. The user can click on that menu to go to their user profile to see their maps and alerts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My new design for the imagery browser:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/portfolio/astro-digital-fetch-new.png&quot; alt=&quot;Astro Digital new imagery browser&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I also worked on some UI redesign to create a cleaner interface. I changed the action icons from dominating green circles to lighter buttons, mimicking the familiar Twitter interface. I differentiated the secondary menu’s text from the text on the rest of the page and increased the contrast between active and inactive tabs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Original design for the user profile page:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/portfolio/astro-digital-profile-ui-old.png&quot; alt=&quot;Astro Digital old profile page&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My new design for the user profile page:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/portfolio/astro-digital-profile-ui-new.png&quot; alt=&quot;Astro Digital new profile page&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2015/08/15/astro-digital.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2015/08/15/astro-digital.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>portfolio</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>India Lights</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/portfolio/india-nighttime.png&quot; alt=&quot;India night lights&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
While working at &lt;a href=&quot;https://developmentseed.org/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Development Seed&lt;/a&gt;, I worked on the India Night Lights project, which used 20 years of nighttime satellite imagery to document nighttime light output for 600,000 villages across India. I wrote all of the site content and created supplemental maps to help tell the story of the main interactive map on the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;portfolio-asset&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/portfolio/india-nighttime-daytime.gif&quot; alt=&quot;India nighttime/daytime slider&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;portfolio-caption&quot;&gt;This interactive Leaflet map slider shows the low resolution nighttime imagery on top of high resolution daytime imagery to give a sense of the scale of the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
(Note: The website has not been opened to the public yet, which is why I cannot link to the live site.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2015/07/01/india-lights.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2015/07/01/india-lights.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>portfolio</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Your Body, (Not) Your Choice</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbodynotyourchoice.github.io&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/portfolio/your-body-not-your-choice.png&quot; alt=&quot;Your Body, (Not) Your Choice&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;About:&lt;/strong&gt;
This &lt;a href=&quot;http://yourbodynotyourchoice.github.io&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;interactive map and full-featured website&lt;/a&gt; covers the history of state-level abortion policy in the United States from the Roe v. Wade decision in 1973 through 2014. I worked together with &lt;a href=&quot;http://katiekowalsky.me/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Katie Kowalsky&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://dylanmoriarty.github.io&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Dylan Moriarty&lt;/a&gt; to collect the data, create the interactive map and chart in D3, write content, and code the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your Body, (Not) Your Choice was featured on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://flowingdata.com/2015/03/18/abortion-policies-over-time-and-by-state/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Flowing Data&lt;/a&gt; blog (the nerd highlight of my life!) and won Honorable Mention for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cartogis.org/awards/winners2014.php&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;CaGIS 2014 Map Competition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Process:&lt;/strong&gt;
Read &lt;a href=&quot;http://tolomaps.tumblr.com/tagged/yourbodynotyourchoice&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;my blog posts about the process&lt;/a&gt;.
Katie also &lt;a href=&quot;https://kowalskycartography.wordpress.com/tag/575-final-project/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;wrote a few blog posts on the process&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2015/01/01/your-body-not-your-choice.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2015/01/01/your-body-not-your-choice.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>portfolio</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Grand Tetons</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;portfolio-asset&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../../../../assets/portfolio/grand-tetons-full.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/portfolio/grand-tetons-full.png&quot; alt=&quot;Morning in the Grand Tetons&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;About:&lt;/strong&gt;
I was inspired by Tom Patterson’s work of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shadedrelief.com/landsat8/introduction.html&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;draping satellite imagery over terrain&lt;/a&gt; to create this image of the Grand Tetons. I spent the summer of 2014 reacquainting myself with the U.S. after four years in Colombia by taking a road trip around the country with my family before landing in Madison, Wisconsin. Our stop in the Grand Tetons is near to my heart, where we hiked, kayaked, and enjoyed the stunning mountain scenery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Process:&lt;/strong&gt;
I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blender.org/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Blender&lt;/a&gt; to create shaded relief and Photoshop to create a natural color image from Landsat 5 imagery. I overlaid the shaded relief with the satellite image to make the topography of the area pop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;portfolio-asset&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/portfolio/grand-tetons-process.png&quot; alt=&quot;Morning in the Grand Tetons process&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I debated how to do the shaded relief; typically, when creating relief, the “light source” should come from the top-left of the image in order for the terrain to not appear inverted. However, in the satellite image, it is morning and thus the natural sunlight appears from the right side of the image. After much trial and error, I ultimately decided for the light source to be on the right-hand side of the terrain to accentuate the actual light on the satellite image. That said, I have had one person tell me the terrain looked inverted to them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Daniel Huffman for your &lt;a href=&quot;https://somethingaboutmaps.wordpress.com/2014/10/26/adding-shaded-relief-in-photoshop/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;shaded relief in Photoshop&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://somethingaboutmaps.wordpress.com/2014/01/01/blender-tutorial/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;shaded relief in Blender&lt;/a&gt; tutorials!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2014/12/31/grand-tetons.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2014/12/31/grand-tetons.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>portfolio</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Modern Motherhood</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tolomaps.com/motherhood&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/portfolio/modern-motherhood.png&quot; alt=&quot;Modern Motherhood: A World of Struggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;About:&lt;/strong&gt;
This was my first attempt at using D3 to creative an interactive map, and it was really, really fun. I love mapping issues that I care about, and was taken aback by some of the insight that I gained from exploring the various indicators presented here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was initially inspired to map these topics by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/imagepages/2013/02/17/opinion/17coontz2-map.html&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;this NYTimes map&lt;/a&gt; of maternity leave policies worldwide, which was published right before I got pregnant. It seemed odd that Bogota, Colombia (where I was living at the time) was a better place to have a kid as a working woman than the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am under no illusion that the maternal leave map is actually indicative of the situation in each country; I am aware that in many countries, the official policy may be that women get paid maternal leave, but the reality is that many women don’t have formal employment or may not qualify for other reasons. This is a subject I’d like to explore further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Maternal Death indicator shocked me. In too many countries, the rate is higher than 1:50, meaning that 1 in 50 women will die from some maternal cause.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://tolomaps.com/motherhood&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/portfolio/modern-motherhood-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Modern Motherhood: A World of Struggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2014/11/01/modern-motherhood.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2014/11/01/modern-motherhood.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>portfolio</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Espectro Energy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.espectroenergy.com/map/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/portfolio/espectro-energy.png&quot; alt=&quot;Espectro Energy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;About:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.espectroenergy.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Espectro Energy&lt;/a&gt; was a beta platform built to help people make informed decisions about whether renewable energy can work for them. The user selects information about their energy needs and location, and then the platform gives them different scenarios about how viable renewable energy is for them and what the potential cost would be. Does the user want to focus on decreasing costs? On creating a system with the highest percentage of renewable energy possible? The platform is especially targeted towards users who live in parts of Colombia without access to the electricity grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Process:&lt;/strong&gt;
I worked as project manager and cartographer on this project during my time at &lt;a href=&quot;/resume&quot;&gt;CEELAT&lt;/a&gt; in Bogota, Colombia. I worked closely with web developers, designers, and renewable energy experts to flesh out the technical scope of the project, make sure that everything was running smoothly, and ensure that everyone was on the same page throughout the duration of the project. I conducted user testing with stakeholders, leading to additional improvements to the site. I was also in charge of the map creation, including styling the data in TileMill.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2014/01/01/espectro-energy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/portfolio/2014/01/01/espectro-energy.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>portfolio</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
